SURENDRAN GOPINATHAN







www.linkedin.com/in/surendran-gopinathan



Letterkenny, Co.Donegal

+353 899434636

surendran17.02@gmail.com

SUMMARY

PROFESSIONAL Creative Senior Software Engineer and AWS certified solutions architect offering 4 years of experience working in a SCRUM environment as part of Integration team in Pharmaceutical sector. Thrives within tight deadlines by applying agile development strategies. Self Learner and Highly Adaptable to change and new platforms.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

May 2019 - Aug 2022

Accenture

- Designing and developing solutions as part of middleware/Integration Team in an enterprise application deployed in Weblogic application.
- Experienced in developing rest API's in a enterprise level three tier web application.
- Created Workflows using Camunda Modeler to automate the existing solutions.
- Fully automated a complex integration project that was unmaintainable, which made the business invest more in further enhancements. The time taken to perform the load was reduced from 5 days to 1 hour (97.5 %).
- Created and optimized DB objects to perform complex business logic. Refactored and rewrote large packages into smaller maintainable objects (up to 40% size).
- Worked closely with application owner and Scrum team in all phases of SDLC including analysis, design, coding, unit testing and deployment.
- Played a pivotal role as a part of an Agile Scrum team actively contributing in all Scrum events.
- Serve as primary contact for the client and maintain healthy relationship to guarantee continuous business growth.

Aug 2018 - Apr 2019 Associate Software Engineer

Accenture

- Consult with users, management, and technical personnel to clarify business issues, identify problems and suggest changes/solutions
- Support incident management and problem management.
- Integrating systems by creating interfaces using java and pl/sql as per business logic.
- Manage and coordinate hot fix and maintenance releases.
- Provide support to the business during day-to-day activities and ad-hoc requests during on-call.
- Gain detailed knowledge of all business flows and the application architecture for supported integrations.
- Actively participate in requirement discussion and all phases of product development.

EDUCATION

Meenakshi Sundararajan Engineering College

Bachelor of Engineering

2014 - 2018

8.01/10 GPA

CERTIFICATION

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate
- SKILLS/TOOLS
- Python/Java
- Oracle PL/SQL
- AWS
- Camunda Workflow
- Rest API (Flask/Jersey)
- MongoDB
- Docker/DockerSwarm
- Git
- Maven
- Gitlab CI/CD
- Unix/Bash
- Weblogic
- Kibana
- Postman/API Testing
- IAC (CloudFormation)
- AWS Cognito

INTERESTS

- Competitive Programming
- Technologies
- Table Tennis/Football
- Esports